[CHALLE]
I won't let you go.
Huh! What happened?
[door opens]
Huh?
[ORLAND]
It's you.
[chuckles]
[whooshes]
[CHALLE]
No one will take you.
I gave you my word.
I'll protect you.
[ANNE gasps]
[ORLAND screams]
- [groans]
- [ELLIOTT] Orland!
[panting]
[KING]
Are you all right!?
[gasps]
- [gasps]
- [NADIR] There's so, much blood.
- [KING] Let's take him inside!
- [VALENTINE] This is bad.
[ELLIOTT]
Wait! Be careful!
Daana, Hal!
- Go boil some water now!
- [DAANA] Yes!
- Bandages, too!
- [ORLAND] My eye. He got my eye.
[groans]
So, someone attacked you?
[ORLAND] Yes. The one
we met on the highway.
The red fairy.
[ELLIOTT]
Oh! I thought that was over.
He came back for us?
♪
[CHALLE]
He's been here all along.
[ALL sigh]
He introduced himself as Gladus.
We were fooled.
I should've been more careful.
[panting] If he's Gladus,
then what about Bridget?
[gasps]
It can't be.
[sobs]
Miss Bridget!
Hold on. I should go with you.
Thank you.
Right, then.
I'll fetch a doctor.
And I'll go as well!
You all mean
to abandon your work?
[ALL sigh]
[HUGH]
I'll arrange for the doctor.
I was about to leave anyway.
You don't mind helping us out?
[HUGH]
I gave you Kat, didn't I?
If you don't finish in time
for the Holy
Beginnings Festival,
that will leave me
in a very poor position.
Besides, it's not just the Paige
Workshop's problem,
I'll report it
to the Earl of Downing.
"The red fairy who attacks
silver sugar masters
has reappeared."
I will recommend that
he deploy soldiers for a search.
Lafalle fenn Lafalle, you said?
The red fairy's true name.
It sounds a bit like yours,
doesn't it?
He said we were born
at the same place.
He wanted to make me his ally
but I refused him.
[ANNE]
What sort of "ally"?
[CHALLE]
I don't know. But he said.
[LAFALLE]
To even the odds of it,
I will be taking the girl.
So you'll belong to me as well.
Yes, she is going to be mine.
That doesn't make sense.
If he wants me,
then why did he attack Orland?
It's a warning.
What he means is,
that he can attack you
any time he wants.
We're at his mercy.
♪
[sobs]
[CHALLE]
Don't leave my side.
I will protect you
no matter what.
♪
[knocks]
[ANNE]
Miss Bridget?
[BRIDGET]
I'm the one who put Orland
through all of that, aren't I?
I'm the one who brought Gladus.
I'm the one
who brought that fairy here.
[gasps]
You can't blame this
on yourself!
The red fairy fooled
every last one of us!
That includes me and Challe,
you know!
[BRIDGET] You don't have to lie.
It's my fault. I know that.
[ANNE] No one is holding
this against you!
Stop it! I don't need your pity!
Hmm!
♪
A while ago there was
something Orland said.
[ORLAND]
When we were young children,
we would play together.
As a child,
she was cheerful and sweet but...
[door opens]
[BRIDGET]
You don't know a thing about me!
I'm not even allowed to
blame myself?
So, what then?
What do you propose
I do about this mess?
♪
[ANNE]
I don't know yet.
We just need time to think.
I'm sure there's something
that each of us can do
to get through this.
Let's figure that out first.
[sniffs]
[ELLIOTT]
I have some bad news.
I'm afraid Orland may
lose sight in his left eye.
- [ALL gasp]
- That's awful!
[ELLIOTT] And that isn't all
we have to worry about.
The fairy attacked him first
but Anne's next.
Huh!
[ELLIOTT] If he appears again
and kidnaps her,
we can't continue.
And if another one of us
is injured,
it will slow down
the process too much.
Even if Kat comes to help us,
we won't be able to finish
the work in time.
We'll have to forfeit the job.
Right now, we can still ask
the Silver Sugar Viscount
to lend us the extra sugar
that we need.
It will put us at a disadvantage
for next year's selection,
and it may harm our
workshop's reputation a bit,
but at least
we could finish the job.
[ALL]
Hmm!
[ANNE]
We'll do it ourselves.
We will find a way.
♪
I believe in us.
[NADIR]
I agree! Well said!
Right! If the Head of Artisans
says we'll succeed.
Then there's no point
in questioning ourselves!
[ANNE]
Thank you! Let's work hard!
- [NADIR] Always!
- [KING] We'll get it done.
[VALENTINE]
Of course!
All right!
Back to work in a hurry!
[chuckles]
- Yes, Sir. - Let's grind up...
Mithril Lid Pod? Would
you mind helping us too?
Any time! My pleasure!
[BOTH laugh]
♪
[ANNE] I would be lying
if I said I wasn't afraid.
Lafalle could come back here
at any time.
He could attack in an instant.
But I know that Challe
is here to protect me.
So, I'll concentrate
on the things I can control,
the things I can accomplish.
Anne! The sun is up!
- It's a brand-new day!
- Huh? Oh no! What happened!?
[NOAH]
Come on, sleepyhead!
[ANNE]
Huh! It's cold!
- Noah? What's wrong?
- Why, nothing, Anne!
I'm just doing my job!
I've decided I want to help out
Daana and Hal.
There's more than enough
work to do!
And my first duty is to make
sure everyone's awake on time!
Hmm! Fine with me!
I'm just glad
you're cheering up!
[KAT]
Hey! Is anyone around?
This place is even
more run-down than I thought.
Kat's here!
[ELLIOTT] Sure kept us
in suspense, didn't you?
And then you show up
at the break of dawn!
So am I too early, or too late?
Make up your mind.
[panting]
- [ANNE] Kat!
- Oh. Hey, pipsqueak.
Thank you so much
for coming to help us!
But wait.
We hadn't sent word to you yet.
We won the favor from Hugh,
like we had planned
but I don't know
how you could've known that.
There's only one way, right?
That dimwit came and told
me himself.
Not sure why he found it
so amusing.
Anyway, he also told me
to give you this.
A present?
Huh! Why,
it must be a love letter!
I wonder who it could be from?
Enough! If you want my help,
then show me
to the workroom already!
Right. Fair point.
First, I'll introduce you
to the artisans
you'll be working with.
I'll go deliver
the good news to Mister Glen.
Hmm! Splendid. Thanks.
[GLEN] Alph Hingley is here
and he's going to help us?
[ANNE]
Yes, sir.
Right now, Mister Collins is
introducing him to everyone.
[sighs] I'm glad.
We still have
poor Orland's injury
to worry about, though.
Mister Glen.
Have you seen Miss Bridget
since that happened?
[GLEN]
I have not.
Hmm!
[GLEN] Anne.
I know what you want to say.
Huh?
But right now, I can't stand
to see her face. I'm angry.
Her selfishness
has harmed us all.
And in the case of Orland,
it might have harmed him
irreparably.
[sighs]
You treat other people too well.
Right now, you should worry
about your own problems.
Hmm-mmm!
[ELLIOTT]
Anne!
Coming!
Uh! What is it?
Sorry, but we need to take
a quick little trip.
I've been summoned.
The church wants to talk.
[HEAD PRIEST]
Thank you for coming.
I spoke
to the Silver Sugar Viscount.
He informed me that your work
hasn't been progressing well.
You haven't completed
a single piece,
and you're re-grinding
silver sugar
which hardened after
it was exposed to moisture.
He also said that one
of your artisans
has been injured.
Is that an accurate assessment?
Yes, sir, that's correct.
A month and a half.
Unfortunately,
given the current situation,
your workshop won't be able
to complete the pieces in time.
There's simply
no other conclusion.
We need to think quickly.
Perhaps, the Mercury Workshop
could step in
and finish it on your behalf?
Huh! But that would mean...
[HEAD PRIEST]
You would step down
and their artisans would
create your pieces for you.
[gasps]
[ANNE] I couldn't possibly hand
the project over!
This is our creation!
[HEAD PRIEST] Please don't see
this as a punishment.
You've simply been the victim
of circumstances
beyond your control.
It's a shame,
which is why
we will still pay you
all the reward of 10,000 cress.
How does that sound?
[sighs]
Aha! Sounds lovely!
Mister Collins!
It's very generous!
We don't have to suffer any more
and we still get
the nice reward, don't we?
I refuse!
We've done this as a team.
It was our idea!
I can't bear the thought
of someone else making it!
If we sell off our work now,
we'll be selling our pride
as artisans along with it!
Then there would've been
no point in making it this far!
You think so?
It's not just
what I think, it's a fact!
That's fair enough!
Huh?
[ELLIOTT]
As you've just heard,
our Head of Artisans
does not accept your deal,
and the rest of the workshop
stands beside her.
So, we will decline
your generous offer.
We will complete
the sugar confections
for the Holy
Beginnings Festival.
You're certain?
[ELLIOTT]
There's no need to worry.
We will meet the deadline.
[sighs]
If your stubbornness
causes you to fail the job,
we will not be able
to pay you the reward.
Then, the Paige Workshop's
reputation will hit rock bottom.
We are aware of the risk.
Hmm!
[ELLIOTT] Well, I made all
those confident declarations,
but it's only natural
for the church
to be worried about this.
I'm grateful that we have Kat
to help us,
but considering that Orland
is stuck in bed,
- we haven't gained anyone.
- [ANNE] It's him.
- We are just breaking even.
- One moment!
Could you please stop the cart!?
Well, all right?
Please! You'll catch a cold!
Don't doze off in an alley!
Get up, I'm begging you!
We can't go on like this!
[ANNE]
Cathy!
Huh! It's you!
[ANNE]
Jonas.
- [knocks]
- Huh!
- [creaks]
- Miss! Good to see you!
I just...
Is Orland doing any better?
Mister Orland!
- Miss Bridget is here for you!
- Hold on. I'm not...
One moment.
I'll go bring you some tea.
Huh!
♪
What's wrong?
Are you all right?
My eye? I'll be fine.
No need to worry.
I still have my right one.
I'm not blind.
Luckily, my fingers
are intact, too.
And Kat came to help.
- More importantly.
- Huh!
He didn't hurt you
and that's enough.
[sobs]
It's my fault.
I'm so sorry. Forgive me.
This only happened
because I brought
that fairy here.
[sobs]
It's not much
but could I take care of you?
I won't force you!
I'll leave if you like.
I'm not the person
I used to be, after all.
I'm arrogant and selfish.
I don't expect anyone
to like me or even tolerate me.
♪
Please stay.
You mean it?
♪
[ANNE]
Jonas? Jonas, are you sleeping?
Jonas, I'm talking to you!
[groans]
Anne. Anne?
Wha-What do you want?
Why are you even here
in the first place?
[ANNE]
Stop! Come back!
You remember what happened
at the exhibition, right?
I'm trying to forget, thank you!
Just listen, would you?
The situation isn't
what you think it is!
The things Sammy
did were brought to light
at the exhibition.
Jonas, they proved
your innocence!
Ah!
Really?
Mister Radcliffe said
he wanted to apologize to you.
I heard that he wants
you to come back
to the workshop, as well!
Master Jonas,
this is wonderful news!
We should get ready to go
as soon as we can!
[ANNE]
Jonas?
I won't go back there.
I'm confused.
It was a misunderstanding!
There's no reason
why anyone there would
hold this against you.
So, what's wrong?
♪
If I go to their workshop,
Kieth will still be there.
I'll just be compared to him
and feel wretched
all over again.
Huh! No, wait!
You've said enough, all right!?
[ANNE]
Jonas.
Will you come
to the Paige Workshop instead?
[JONAS]
Paige's Workshop?
Right now, I'm working
on an urgent project with them.
We're having trouble
because we don't have
enough artisans.
With your skills,
you would be a valuable asset.
What do you think?
I can't believe you,
you're always doing
such absurd things.
I'm sick of making confections
and that's the end of it!
If I never touch
silver sugar again
then I'll be happy!
Huh!
I have other plans now.
Things that I would
much rather do.
I can't make it any clearer
than that! Now, goodbye!
What is it you want to do?
Drink until you're sick?
Pass out in a cold, dirty alley
and make Cathy worry about you?
Do nothing
and keep making up excuses?
[sighs]
[JONAS]
Go away.
Not yet. Not 'til you can at
least be honest with me, Jonas!
Enough! Someone like
you could never understand me!
Huh!
What do you mean,
"someone like me?" Why?
You can still make confections,
like before.
Uh!
I knew it. You haven't given up.
In your heart,
you still want to do it.
[JONAS]
No! I told you! I...
After all that's happened,
how could, I how could I?
[sobs]
But I want to.
Master Jonas.
[sobs]
[CHALLE] It would seem
we've recruited a new artisan.
Seems like
he's got self-esteem issues
but he might be reliable
in a pinch.
Let's hope.
[KAT]
What did you drag in?
Uh...
Actually, I think I'll leave.
[ANNE]
Wait! This is Jonas Anders!
He's an artisan from the
Radcliffe Workshop school!
He used to be my rival!
"Rival?" Then,
he must be pretty skilled, huh?
All right! We'll see!
- We could sure use your help!
- Jonas, come here.
[sighs]
[KAT]
Nice craftsmanship, right?
I was impressed, as well.
Alas, these take an
absurd amount of time to make.
And they're also very delicate.
If you handle them wrong,
they'll collapse.
I want to make sure
that you understand
what's being asked of you.
- Huh!
- Hmm!
Hmm!
[gasps]
What's wrong?
[whooshes]
[footsteps]
[panting]
I messed up.
[CHALLE]
Lafalle's back.
What happened?
Why has he done this to you?
[groans]
[chuckles]
[CHALLE] Elliott, you must have
a message from him. Tell us.
[ELLIOTT]
Can't do that.
[CHALLE]
Don't worry! Say it!
Hand over Anne,
he'll release me in exchange,
he said. I'm sorry.
How cruel!
[whooshes]
[clangs]
Challe, please don't!
[gasps]
Anne!
It's fine.
♪
[grunts]
- [JONAS] Someone help!
- [KAT] Be careful! - Elliott!
It's your turn, Challe.
Come here. Slowly.
♪
[footsteps]
- Stop it!
- You bastard!
[LAFALLE]
Oh, quiet.
If you misbehave,
then her pretty, little head
will come off.
Keep walking,
with your hands in sight.
I wouldn't try anything rash,
or I may, in my distress,
cut off one of Anne's legs.
I will have your wing now.
♪
[ALL gasp]
[gasps]
[LAFALLE]
Take it from him, Anne.
♪
Splendid.
[groans]
[ANNE]
No, Challe!
That settles it!
Seems this is, indeed,
your wing.
Now, get on that horse there.
I readied it just for you,
Challe.
I thought you would appreciate
its beautiful black coat.
[grunts]
[purring]
[gasps]
♪
[neighs]